[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：现在是更好的部分。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And now the better parts.
这就是Antoine de Saint-Exupery
So this is Antoine de Saint-Exupery.
在航空业非常危险的时候，他是一名飞行员。
He was an aviator back at the time when aviation was really dangerous.
我们以前就是这么称呼飞行员的，但他是个飞行员。
That's what we used to call pilots, but he was an aviator.
这真的很危险，因为飞机坠毁了。
It was really dangerous because the planes crashed.
在他的职业生涯中他经历了几次车祸
And he experienced several crashes during his career and
几乎所有人都活了下来。
survived almost all of them.
他曾经试图创造从巴黎到西贡的空速记录
He was once trying to set the air speed record from Paris to Saigon and
他的飞机坠毁在埃及，在撒哈拉沙漠开罗附近。
his plane crashed in Egypt, near Cairo out in the Sahara Desert.
他没有准备好在沙漠中生存。
And he was not prepared for survival in the desert.
他在那里表现得非常糟糕，遭受了严重的脱水。
He did very badly there, suffered terrible dehydration.
脱水得太厉害以至于他停止了出汗，
Dehydrated so much that he stopped sweating,
在沙漠里做这件事真的很危险。
which is a really dangerous thing to do in the desert.
遭受了可怕的幻觉。
Suffered terrible hallucinations.
幸运的是，他被一个懂得如何治疗严重疾病的人救了出来。
Fortunately he was rescued by someone who understood how to treat severe
脱水，他活了下来，康复了。
dehydration and he survived and recovered.
随着战争的开始移居美国，成为一名作家
Moved to America as the war is beginning, becomes a writer and
原来他是一位才华横溢的作家。
turns out he's a brilliant writer.
他写了最著名的儿童书籍之一，“小王子”。
He writes one of the most famous children's books, The Little Prince.
它讲的是一个被困在沙漠中的飞行员
Which is about an aviator who is stranded in the desert
他被一个住在小行星上的奇怪的小男孩拜访，他有自杀倾向。
who is visited by a strange little boy who lives on an asteroid and is suicidal.
就像所有最好的儿童书籍一样，这不是一本真正的儿童书籍，是的。
Like all the best children's books, it's not really a children's book, yeah.
他还写了其他的书。
And he wrote other books, too.
他写了一些关于航空的很好的书
He wrote some very good books about aviation books and
针对成年人的书籍。
books aimed at grownups.
在其中一篇文章中，他写了史上最好的句子之一。
In one of them, he has one of the best sentences ever written.
他说，似乎完美并不是在没有更多事情要做的时候才达到的。
He says it seems that perfection is attained not when there is nothing more to
加，但当没有更多要减去的东西时，这就太棒了。
add, but when there is nothing more to subtract, which is just brilliant.
我看过这句话一遍又一遍地重复引用。
I've seen this quoted requoted over and over again.
它在所有的地方和工程设计中都被使用，
It's used all over the place and in engineering design,
任何创造性的需要某种纪律的东西。
anything that's creative that requires some kind of discipline.
这只是一句精彩的引语
It's just a brilliant quote and
他在谈论飞机的设计，但似乎什么都谈。
he's talking about the design of airplanes but it seems to talk about everything.
我认为这对于编程来说特别有意义，
And I think it's especially telling for programming,
因为我们和完美有一种特殊的关系，对吧？
because we have a special relationship with perfection, right?
我们的程序必须完美否则就不能正常工作。
That our programs have to be perfect or they're not gonna work correctly.
他给了我们一些关于如何达到完美的洞察力。
And he gives us some insight as to how perfection is attained.
它是通过删除东西，而不是通过添加东西。
It's by removing things, it's not by adding things.
我认为我们也可以将它应用于编程语言。
And I think we can also apply it to programming languages.
因为我们在那里有类似的事情
Because we have similar things going on there
我们的大多数编程语言倾向于添加东西。
that most of our programming languages tend to want to add things.
但我认为大部分可以通过删除东西来改善。
But I think most of them could be improved by removing things.
这就是好的部分的原则从何而来。
And that's where the principle of the good parts comes from.
如果一个功能有时有用有时很危险
That if a feature is sometimes useful and sometimes dangerous and
如果有更好的选择。
if there is a better option.
总是使用更好的选择。
Always use the better option.
令我惊讶的是，这是一个有争议的声明。
And it surprises me that this is a controversial statement.
现在有很多人说我不想用更好的选择。
Now there are lots of people out there who say I don't wanna use a better option.
你不能让我用更好的选择。
You can't make me use the better option.
好像变得更好就足够了，但事实并非如此。
It's like it being better should be enough,but it's not.
我认为这来自于一个根本性的误解
I think that comes from a fundamental misunderstanding about
我们做的是什么。
what it is that we do.
我们并不是为了使用语言的每一个特性而付费的。
We are not paid to use every feature of the language.
在项目结束时，永远不会有经理拿着剪贴板说
At the end of a project there is never a manager with a clipboard saying
确实使用了WITH语句，您是否省略了任何分号？
did use a with statement, did you leave out any semicolons?
您在运算符XII中使用逗号吗？
Did you use commas in operator XII?.
不，没人会这么做。
No, no, nobody's doing that.
我们受雇于编写运行良好的程序
We are paid to write programs that work well and
没有错误，但这就是问题所在。
are free of error, but that's what it's all about.
现在没有错误了，这是从哪里来的？
Now free of error, where did that come from?
结果是没有错误的始终是第一要求。
What turns out free of error has always been the first requirement.
只是我们很少做到这一点，
It's just we so rarely attain it,
很容易忘记这是最重要的事情。
it's easy to forget that it's the most important thing.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我想这就是为什么它从来没有得到支付。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It's why it's never gotten paid, I guess.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以好的编程语言应该教你。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So good programming language should teach you.
我建议大家尽可能多地学习语言。
I recommend everybody learn as many languages as you can.
因为每一种语言都会给你一些新的视角，
Because every language will give you some new perspective on something,
也许会把你推向一个新的范式。
maybe push you into a new paradigm.
你可以把你学到的东西
And you can take the things that you learned and
将它应用于你知道的所有其他语言。
apply it to all the other languages you know.
每个人都应该学习尽可能多的语言。
Everybody should learn as many languages as they can.
在我的职业生涯中教给我最多的语言是JavaScript。
And the language in my career that has taught me the most has been JavaScript.
我花了一段时间从语言中学习，因为，
And it took a while for me to to learn from the language, because well,
我在JavaScript中犯了你可能犯的每一个错误。
I made every mistake in JavaScript that you could make.
从第一个开始，最糟糕的一个。
Starting with the first one, the worst one.
在我开始写作之前，我认为我不需要学习这门语言，
I didn't think I needed to learn the language before I started writing in it,
以至于我如此鄙视它。
that I had so much contempt for it.
当我第一次看到JavaScript时，我认为这是我见过的最愚蠢的事情。
The first time I saw JavaScript I thought it was the stupidest thing I'd ever seen.
结果发现，
And it turns out,
我并不是完全错了，但我也不是完全对的。
I wasn't completely wrong, but I wasn't completely right either.
最终，我做到了
Eventually, I did and
我在写JavaScript的时候一直在咒骂，这让我非常生气。
I was cursing all the time I was writing a JavaScript that made me very, very angry.
所以最终，我决定学习这门语言。
So eventually, I decided to learn the language.
所以我得到了标准，你可以从网站上免费下载
So I got the standard, which you get free off of the site and
读了它，惊讶地发现里面有Lambdas。
read it, and was surprised to discover that it had lambdas in it.
如果它有第一类函数作为具有词汇闭包的第一类值，
If it had functions with first class as first class values with lexical closure,
我不知道它在里面。
which I had no idea that it was in there.
布兰登故意放进去的。
Brendan put it in there intentionally.
这不是偶然进入语言的东西，但是
That's not something that gets into the language by accident, but
他没告诉任何人。
he didn't tell anybody.
所以我在阅读标准时发现了这一点，
And so I discovered it in reading the standard and was wow,
这改变了一切。
this changes everything.
在这一点上，我与语言的关系发生了变化。
And at that point my relationship with the language changed.
在这一点上，他终于能够开始教我一些东西
And at that point, he was able to finally start teaching me things and
他教会了我很多东西。
he has taught me a lot.
所以我用JavaScript做的一件事就是编写JSLint。
So one of the things I did with JavaScript was I wrote JSLint.
因为我需要一个工具来帮助我
Because I needed a tool to help me
避免使用该语言的所有陷阱。
avoid all of the traps that are in that language.
他们是来打败我的。
That are there to defeat me.
而且JSLint在JavaScript方面比我聪明得多。
And JSLint turns out is much smarter about JavaScript than I am.
我最初的直觉是什么是语言的好特性什么是坏的
My initial intuitions about what were good features of languages what were bad
是极其不可靠的。
were extremely unreliable.
而JSLint总是非常擅长
Whereas JSLint was always very good at
总是引导我找到正确的观点。
always directing me to the correct point of view.
为了找出错误，我们可以机械地做什么？
What is it that we can do mechanically in order to find mistakes?
因为这就是我需要做的，为了让我的程序更完美。
Because that's what I need to do in order to try to make my programs more perfect.
JSLint教会了我大量的编程知识。
And JSLint has taught me an enormous amount about programming.